{"tossups": [{"question": "In a 2011 book, Deborah Lipstadt argued that an earlier interpretation of this man mischaracterized him as \"unaware.\" In another book, this man was labeled a fanatical \"joiner\" who joined groups to de ne himself, and he was described as someone who battles language using self-invented cliche\u0301s and stock phrases. This man's claim that he had spent his life obeying Kant's categorical imperative was rebutted by a philosopher who claimed that this man failed to recognize the fundamental \"golden rule.\" This man is the title subject of a 1963 book, originally written for the New Yorker, that is o en reprinted showing him in a glass cage in a courtroom. A \"report on the banality of evil\" is titled a er, for 10 points, what Nazi of cial whose trial \"in Jerusalem\" was analyzed by Hannah Arendt?", "answer": "Adolf Eichmann [or Otto Adolf Eichmann; accept Eichmann in Jerusalem: A Report on the Banality of Evil]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Adolf Eichmann</u></b> [or <b><u>Otto Adolf Eichmann</u></b>; accept <b><u>Eichmann in Jerusalem: A Report on the Banality of Evil</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Adolf Eichmann", "Adolf Eichmann", "Otto Adolf Eichmann", "Eichmann in Jerusalem: A Report on the Banality of Evil"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This number is the base of the q term that appears twice in Dedekind's eta (DAY-duh-kind's AY-tuh) function and that is known as the \"nome\" in number theory. This number is the base in the in nite sum that defines Jacobi's theta function. When this number is raised to the power of \"pi times the square root of 163,\" it is shockingly close to an integer and known as Ramanujan's (rah-MAHN-uh-jahn's) constant. In Stirling's approximation for n factorial, this number is raised to the minus n. For the limit as n goes to infinity, this number is equal to the nth power of the quantity \"one plus one over n.\" The Taylor series for \"this number to the x power\" is an in nite sum, from zero, of \"x to the n\" over \"n factorial\" because the derivative of this number to the x power is still this number to the x power is still this number to the x power. For 10 points, what number, sometimes named for Euler, is approximately 2.718?", "answer": "e [or exponential; accept Euler's number or Euler's constant before \"Euler\"]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>e</u></b> [or <b><u>exponential</u></b>; accept <b><u>Euler's number</u></b> or <b><u>Euler's constant</u></b> before \"Euler]", "acceptable": ["e", "e", "exponential", "Euler's number", "Euler's constant"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a story by this author, Jonathan converts his money into egg rashers, only to be robbed shortly thereafter. This author wrote a novel in which the protagonist is initially favored, but then imprisoned, by a man he calls \"Wintabota,\" or \"destroyer of guns.\" A novel by this author of \"Civil Peace\" includes the fable of a tortoise that grew wings and dined with the birds, only to be smashed when it tried to dive back to earth. In this man's follow-up to that novel, Clara refuses to marry the protagonist, who studies law in England on a scholarship from a \"progressive union\" and accepts a bribe to pay for Clara's abortion. For 10 points, what author of Arrow of God wrote about Obi in No Longer at Ease and created Obi's grandfather, Okonkwo, in Things Fall Apart?", "answer": "Chinua Achebe [or Albert Chinualumogu Achebe]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Chinua <b><u>Achebe</u></b> [or <b><u>Albert Chinualumogu Achebe</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Chinua Achebe", "Achebe", "Albert Chinualumogu Achebe"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Industrially, this compound and hydrogen sul de are removed during sweetening by using scrubbers treated with alkanol\u00c2\u00b7amines. Jeffrey Long's group at Berkeley has pioneered the use of di\u00c2\u00b7amine-modi ed Mg-D\u00c2\u00b7O\u00c2\u00b7B\u00c2\u00b7D\u00c2\u00b7C metal-organic frameworks to adsorb this compound. The Sleipnir project off the Norwegian coast collects this compound in deep saline aquifers. Enhanced coal bed methane recovery consists of  ooding an unmineable coal seam with a supercritical  uid form of this compound. Stimulating a phytoplankton bloom in the open ocean with iron fertilization has been  oated as a route to decreasing the concentration of this compound in the atmosphere. For 10 points, capture and sequestration of what anthropogenic greenhouse gas has the goal of mitigating global warming? ", "answer": "carbon dioxide [or CO2]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>carbon dioxide</u></b> [or <b><u>CO2</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["carbon dioxide", "carbon dioxide", "CO2"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In Second Chronicles, this man writes a letter to King Jehoram of Judah, warning that God will kill Jehoram for leading the inhabitants of Jerusalem astray. Rabbinic interpretations of an incident involving this man on Mount Horeb are o en cited as the reason a chair is set aside for him at the brit milah. In chapter nine of the Gospel of Luke, Moses and this man appear and converse with Jesus during the Trans guration. In First Kings, this man summons  re on Mount Carmel, thereby proving the superiority of Yahweh over Jezebel. In the Book of Malachi, this man is prophesied to return before the Day of Judgment. For 10 points, name this biblical prophet who successfully challenged heathen priests before he was taken up to heaven in a  aming chariot", "answer": "Elijah [or Elias; or Eliyahu; or Ilyas; do not accept or prompt on \"Elisha\"]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Elijah</u></b> [or <b><u>Elias</u></b>; or <b><u>Eliyahu</u></b>; or <b><u>Ilyas</u></b>; do not accept or prompt on \"Elisha\"]", "acceptable": ["Elijah", "Elijah", "Elias", "Eliyahu", "Ilyas"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["Elisha"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A plaster sculpture that once stood in this building complex provided the name of its Courtyard of the White Horse. This complex includes a horseshoe-shaped double staircase designed by Jean Androuet du Cerceau (awn-droo-AY du ser-SOH). A bronze sculpture showing forest animals drinking water streaming from an urn illustrates the legend that a hunting dog named Bliaud (blee-OHD) discovered a spring at this complex; that bronze lunette sculpture shows a stag head protruding above the title water nymph and was created by Benvenuto Cellini as the tympanum for a gate at this palace's entrance. Francesco Primaticcio (pree-mah-TEE-chee-oh) and Rosso Fiorentino were members of a school of Mannerist painters that formed at this palace at the invitation of Francis I. For 10 points, name this French palace complex to the southeast of Paris.", "answer": "Palace of Fontainebleau [or Cha\u0302teau de Fontainebleau]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Palace of Fontainebleau</u></b> [or <b><u>Cha\u0302teau de Fontainebleau</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Palace of Fontainebleau", "Palace of Fontainebleau", "Cha\u0302teau de Fontainebleau"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In Drosophila (droh-SAW-fih-lah), the Loquacious protein activates this process by suppressing Stellate. Controls called \"scramble\" are most o en applied in experiments using this process. A protein central to this process, which has a piwi (pee-wee) domain, was named because its Arabidopsis (ah-RAB-ih-DOP-sis) mutants look like octopi. This process, whose mechanism was  rst discovered in the genes lin-4 and let-27 (LIN-four and LET-27), increases the activity of cyto\u00c2\u00b7plasmic P bodies and is activated when Drosha binds to Pasha. This process progresses when the Argonaute nuclease, a component of the RISC (\"risk\"), processes the remnants of Dicer cleavage. Craig Mello and Andrew Fire won a Nobel for discovering the mechanism of this process in C. elegans (see eh-leh-ganz). For 10 points, name this technique that uses s\u00c2\u00b7i\u00c2\u00b7RNAs and m\u00c2\u00b7i\u00c2\u00b7RNAs to knock down a gene.", "answer": "RNA interference [or RNAi; prompt on RNA silencing; prompt on gene knockdown or gene knockout or gene repression or similar answers]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "RNA <b><u>interference</u></b> [or <b><u>RNAi</u></b>; prompt on <u>RNA silencing</u>; prompt on <u>gene knockdown</u> or <u>gene knockout</u> or <u>gene repression</u> or <u>similar answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["RNA interference", "interference", "RNAi"], "promptable": ["RNA silencing", "gene knockdown", "gene knockout", "gene repression", "similar answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "While besieging Kerak (ker-ACK) on the day that a princess of this name married Humphrey of Toron, Saladin was convinced not to bombard the tower in which the newlyweds spent their wedding night. By marrying Yolande of Brienne (yoh-LAHND of bree-EN), who had this regnal name, Frederick II brought the Kingdom of Jerusalem into Hohenstaufen (ho-hen-SHTOW-fen) control. The inconclusive Battle of Toro won a woman with this name her countrymen's support in a succession dispute against her half niece, Joanna la Beltraneja (zhoh-ah-nah la bel-trah-NAY-zhah); with her husband, that woman with this name expelled the Jews from her country in the Alhambra Decree and completed the Reconquista by conquering Grenada. For 10 points, give the name of the Castilian queen who sponsored Christopher Columbus and ruled Spain with her husband, Ferdinand of Aragon.", "answer": " Isabella [accept Isabella I of Jerusalem or Isabella II of Jerusalem or Isabella I of Castile]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Isabella</u></b> [accept <b><u>Isabella I of Jerusalem</u></b> or <b><u>Isabella II of Jerusalem</u></b> or <b><u>Isabella I of Castile</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Isabella", "Isabella", "Isabella I of Jerusalem", "Isabella II of Jerusalem", "Isabella I of Castile"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poem by Richard Brautigan reimagines this event as a rape at the hands of \"an evil  sherman who was dressed in clothes that had no childhood.\" Upon learning of this event, a character offers to eat a crocodile and invites mountains to pile up over him so as to \"make Ossa (oh-sah) like a wart.\" Before this event, its central character claims that \"you must wear your rue with a difference\" and sings \"hey non nonny, nonny.\" This event occurs offstage when an \"envious sliver\" breaks off a willow that \"grows aslant a brook,\" as reported by Gertrude to the victim's brother, Laertes (LAIR-teez). It occurs a er a woman is driven mad by the death of Polonius and the behavior of a man who tells her to \"get thee to a nunnery.\" For 10 points, name this fatal event that befalls a young woman in Shakespeare's Hamlet.", "answer": "death of Ophelia [or drowning of Ophelia; accept answers implying that Ophelia has died or drowned or committed suicide]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>death of Ophelia</u></b> [or <b><u>drowning of Ophelia</u></b>; accept <b><u>answers implying that Ophelia has died</u></b> or <b><u>drowned</u></b> or <b><u>committed suicide</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["death of Ophelia", "death of Ophelia", "drowning of Ophelia", "answers implying that Ophelia has died", "drowned", "committed suicide"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In the Odyssey, Nestor relates that this man marooned a court bard on an island to be eaten by crows and seagulls. He was conceived when his mother, while washing clothes stained with the blood of a sacri cial ewe, was raped by a masked man, whose sword she managed to steal; as a child, this son of Pelopia (peh-LOH-pee-ah) was commanded to use that sword to murder a prisoner revealed to be his own father, Thyestes (\"thigh\"-ESS-teez), leading him to kill Atreus (AY-tree-us) instead. This man's lover killed her husband by trapping him in a net and beheading him with an axe, motivated by anger at the sacri ce of her daughter Iphigenia; both that woman and this Mycenaean (my-SEE-nee-an) usurper were slain by Orestes, who was avenging his father. For 10 points, what lover of Clytemnestra seized power while Agamemnon was  ghting at Troy?", "answer": "Aegisthus [or Aegisthos]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Aegisthus</u></b> [or <b><u>Aegisthos</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Aegisthus", "Aegisthus", "Aegisthos"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one painting, this artist showed a man wearing red pointing a pole forward as the title animal is transported across a river; that painting, The White Horse, was the  rst in this man's series of large-scale \"six-footers.\" In a work painted a er the death of his wife, Maria, he showed a rainbow extending over an ash tree and a building. Delacroix revised his Massacre at Chios (KEE-ose) a er viewing the work of this artist, who painted a jarring blue-and-black background and a double rainbow in his depiction of Stonehenge, 1835. This painter of several views of Salisbury Cathedral created many depictions of the River Stour (stoor), including a painting that includes Willy Lott's cottage on its le  side. For 10 points, name this English Romantic painter of Dedham Vale and The Hay Wain.", "answer": "John Constable", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "John <b><u>Constable</u></b>", "acceptable": ["John Constable", "Constable"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In an oligopolistic market, the time series plot of this value may take on a sawtooth shape as a result of dynamic equilibria, as predicted by the theory of \"Edgeworth cycles.\" In a paper on the \"theory\" of this value \"and business behavior,\" Robert Lowe Hall and Charles Hitch theorized that  rms' original decisions regarding this value explained the initial location of a \"kink.\" Unlike the Cournot model of oligopolies, the Bertrand model takes this value as the choice variable. The \"kinked\" demand curve was formulated to explain why this quantity, like wages, is sometimes \"sticky.\" A \"taker\" of this quantity lacks \"market power,\" which is the ability of an economic actor to set this quantity. For 10 points, name this quantity that is the payment demanded for a good or service.", "answer": "price(s)", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>price</u></b>", "acceptable": ["price", "price"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "s"}, {"question": "Nitrogen  xation is assayed by an experiment in which this compound is reduced. The polymer of this compound, doped with iodine, was the  rst conducting polymer discovered. Traditionally, Reppe (\"REP\"-puh) chemistry refers to carbonylation of this compound. This compound reacts with 1,3-buta\u00c2\u00b7diene (\"one three\" byu-tah-\"DIE\"-een) to give 1,4-cyclo\u00c2\u00b7hexa\u00c2\u00b7diene in a Diels\u00c2\u2013Alder reaction. The di\u00c2\u00b7cyano derivative of this compound has the highest known adiabatic  ame temperature. Calcium carbide reacts with water to form this compound, three moles of which can be combined to make one mole of benzene with no byproducts. This compound's two protons each have a p\u00c2\u00b7K\u00c2\u00b7a around 25. It is usually the \"fuel\" in oxy-fuel cutting. For 10 points, name this compound with formula C2H2 (C-2-H-2), the simplest alkyne, which is used in welding torches.", "answer": "acetylene [or ethyne; accept C2H2 before \"C2H2\"]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>acetylene</u></b> [or <b><u>ethyne</u></b>; accept <b><u>C2H2</u></b> before \"C2H2]", "acceptable": ["acetylene", "acetylene", "ethyne", "C2H2"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a novel by this author, a man explains his intent to follow in the footsteps of a preacher who went into the wilderness to  nd his soul, only to discover that all he had was a \"little piece of a great big soul.\" Henry is surprised to  nd that his wife looks \"strong\" a er she is visited by a tinker in a story by this author in which Elisa Allen takes pride in growing the title  owers. A novel by this author of \"The Chrysanthemums\" ends with a girl who has recently given birth to a stillborn baby smiling as she breastfeeds a starving old man in a barn; in that novel by this man, Jim Casy dies leading striking migrant workers, and Tom Joad's family journeys to California. For 10 points, name this novelist who depicted the hardships of Dust Bowl\u00c2\u2013era tenant farmers in The Grapes of Wrath.", "answer": "John Steinbeck [or John Ernst Steinbeck Jr.]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "John <b><u>Steinbeck</u></b> [or <b><u>John Ernst Steinbeck Jr.</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["John Steinbeck", "Steinbeck", "John Ernst Steinbeck Jr."], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In the last of three 1941 speeches, a member of this organization spoke out against the state-driven forced euthanasia program Aktion T4. Julius Bachem (YU-lee-us BAH-kem) called for his party to weaken its association with this organization in the article \"We Must Come Down from the Tower.\" This organization smuggled and distributed a pamphlet titled \"With Burning Concern,\" or Mit brennender Sorge (ZOR-guh), to protest violations of the Reichskonkordat (RIKES-\"concord\"-aht), a treaty that guaranteed its rights. The Zentrum party represented this organization, which was especially powerful in southern Baden-Wu\u0308rttemberg (bah-den-VURT-em-berg) and Bavaria. Adalbert Falk issued the May Laws to reduce this organization's power as part of Otto von Bismarck's Kulturkampf. For 10 points, name this organization that criticized Nazism under Pius XII (\"the twel\u5005h\").", "answer": "Roman Catholic Church [accept answers specifying the Roman Catholic Church in Germany; accept Roman Catholicism; prompt on \"the Church\" or similar answers]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Roman Catholic Church</u></b> [accept <b><u>answers specifying the Roman Catholic Church in Germany</u></b>; accept <b><u>Roman Catholicism</u></b>; prompt on the <u>Church</u> or <u>similar answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["Roman Catholic Church", "Roman Catholic Church", "answers specifying the Roman Catholic Church in Germany", "Roman Catholicism"], "promptable": ["Church", "similar answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a speech given in the year of this election, a woman recounted getting beaten in the Montgomery County jail and said \"I question America.\" The winning side in this election aired the \"Confessions of a Republican\" ad. At the DNC before this election, Fannie Lou Hamer's emotional testimony failed to convince party elites to seat the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party. In an acceptance speech before this election, the Republican candidate declared that \"extremism in the defense of liberty is no vice.\" The quote \"we must either love each other, or we must die\" ended an ad that aired before this election and that began with a girl picking petals off a  ower. The \"Daisy\" ad aired before, for 10 points, what presidential election in which Lyndon Johnson defeated Barry Goldwater?", "answer": "U.S. presidential election of 1964 [prompt on \"'64\"]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>U.S. presidential election of 1964</u></b> [prompt on <u>'64</u>]", "acceptable": ["U.S. presidential election of 1964", "U.S. presidential election of 1964"], "promptable": ["'64"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Fernando Vergara photographed female members of this group switching between their military uniforms and everyday clothing. A change in government policy regarding this organization was partly caused by the rise of BACRIM (bah-KREEM) bandit groups. A U.S. operation that mostly targets this organization controversially uses aerial fumigation to wipe out its main source of income. This group, which sometimes collaborated with the National Liberation Army, is currently led by a man who goes by the name Timochenko. Juan Manuel Santos won the 2016 Nobel Peace Prize for negotiating a peace treaty with this group, which was later renegotiated a er the treaty was voted down by popular referendum. For 10 points, name this Marxist guerrilla organization in Colombia.", "answer": "FARC\u00c2\u2013EP [or Fuerzas Armadas Revolucionarias de Colombia\u00c2\u2013Eje\u0301rcito del Pueblo; or Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia\u00c2\u2013People's Army]", "category": "Current Events", "subcategory": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>FARC\u00c2\u2013EP</u></b> [or <b><u>Fuerzas Armadas Revolucionarias de Colombia\u00c2\u2013Eje\u0301rcito del Pueblo</u></b>; or <b><u>Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia\u00c2\u2013People's Army</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["FARC\u00c2\u2013EP", "FARC\u00c2\u2013EP", "Fuerzas Armadas Revolucionarias de Colombia\u00c2\u2013Eje\u0301rcito del Pueblo", "Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia\u00c2\u2013People's Army"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man's last symphony employs a \"distant choir\" of violins and harps that play in a separate rhythm from the rest of the orchestra in the  nale; the third movement of that piece has a fugue based on this man's  rst string quartet and was later arranged by his friend Bernard Herrmann. The  rst movement of another work by this man consists of the same 27 measures three times, though the violin and cello are silent for the  rst and second iteration, respectively. The song \"Columbia, Gem of the Ocean\" is quoted in this composer's Second Symphony, his Holidays Symphony, and a piece with a movement titled \"Putnam's Camp.\" A symphony called The Camp Meeting and the Concord Sonata are by, for 10 points, what American composer of Three Places in New England?", "answer": "Charles Ives", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Charles Ives</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Charles Ives", "Charles Ives"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author wrote a play in an unconventional three-act form in which Hydaspes and Asaph (\"high\"-DASS-peez and AY-saf) are of cers of King Ahasuerus (ah-hah-soo-AIR-us), who is convinced by the title character to stop a plotted massacre of Jews. That play by this man, Esther, includes extensive musical choruses, which he also used in a biblical drama in which a queen who worships Baal is killed when the high priest Joad (JOH-ad) brings Joash (JOH-ash) to power. In another play by this author, Hermione (AIR-mee-\"own\") vows to kill herself a er Pyrrhus (PEER-us) dies, which results in Orestes going insane. This master of alexandrine verse described an illicit love affair between Aricie and Hippolyte (ar-ee-SEE and ip-oh-LEET) in a play in which the title character tells Theseus of her incestuous feelings. For 10 points, what French playwright wrote the tragedies Athalie, Andromaque, and Phedre (ah-tah-LEE, ahn-droh-MAHK, and FAY-druh)?", "answer": "Jean-Baptiste Racine", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Jean-Baptiste <b><u>Racine</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Jean-Baptiste Racine", "Racine"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A general from this country kept a mountain goat as his mascot and came to international prominence a er giving an interview to German reporter Randolph Baumann. The fatal 1998 heart attack of this country's dictator is called the \"coup from heaven.\" This country executed \"Operation Tiger Claw\" under a general nicknamed the \"Black Scorpion.\" Its  rst prime minister, Abubakar Balewa (AH-bu-bah-kar bah-LAY-wah), was overthrown in the \"Revolt of the Five Majors.\" This country was suspended from the Commonwealth of Nations a er its dictator, Sani Abacha (SAH-nee ah-BAH-cha), ordered the execution of a man leading protests against environmental atrocities committed by Royal Dutch Shell. Ken Saro-Wiwa (sah-roh-WEE-wah) was executed in, for 10 points, what African country from which Igbo nationalists seceded to form Biafra (bee-AHF-rah)?", "answer": "Nigeria [or Federal Republic of Nigeria]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Nigeria</u></b> [or <b><u>Federal Republic of Nigeria</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Nigeria", "Nigeria", "Federal Republic of Nigeria"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The  ux-freezing theorem can be derived from integrating the ideal version of this law for M\u00c2\u00b7H\u00c2\u00b7D, which states that the electric  eld plus the velocity  eld crossed with the magnetic  eld equals zero. The proportionality constant for the microscopic version of this law is the electron density times the \"square of fundamental charge\" times the \"mean free time between collisions,\" all over mass, in the Drude (drood) model. The microscopic analog of this law is that the current density equals the conductivity times the electric  eld. Diodes do not follow this law because their I\u00c2\u2013V curves are nonlinear; if the curves were linear, the slope would be the proportionality constant for this law. For 10 points, what law states that the voltage between two points in a circuit is equal to the current times the resistance?", "answer": "Ohm's law", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ohm's</u></b> law", "acceptable": ["Ohm's law", "Ohm's"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}